David Genest

80 Tanglewood Dr, Lake Oswego | 971.271.0993 | drwgenest@gmail.com

Summary

I am a self-taught web developer with a degree in computer science, seeking a development role. My background comes from 20+ years of experience as a technical business analyst in the financial services industry performing both development functions (SQL, OmniScript, Exstream Dialogue) and traditional analyst functions (requirements gathering, testing, user support). As an analyst, I am used to communicating clearly between all levels of business and technical resources. Over the last year I sharpened my Javascript skills by building apps in a Node.js environment and completing the Full Stack Developer certification at freeCodeCamp.com. My projects primarily used React/Redux/Express with features like social login and RESTful APIs, and incorporating libraries such as Foundation 6, D3.js, Socket.io and mongoDB – you can view some of them here: https://genestd.github.io/portfolio2

Experience

Sr. Business Analyst, Enterprise Iron, Dec 2012 - Mar 2017

Worked as a Solutions Analyst and Lead BA supporting onboarding of TIAA clients to an Oracle-based multivendor payroll interface.

- BA on Agile software project replacing multiple legacy systems with an Angular/Mongo application
- Lead BA on multi-phase project onboarding a top-5 client. Performed testing, solution design, issue triage and production incident support throughout the project as client implemented new features to extend proprietary STAC/MVAS payroll interface
- Designed and developed customized solutions to client data requirements; performed Oracle reporting; provided IT support for production incidents
- SME for STAC service tracking/ contribution calculation engine providing training, tech support and requirements analysis
- Data Quality created real-time audit queries of customer contribution and eligibility calculations

Business Systems Analyst III - Asset Mgmt, The Standard, Jun 2004 - Dec 2012 Worked as a lead business analyst with roles in development, tech support and SDLC projects

- Developer: Utilize OmniScript to provide customized Retirement Plan client transactions, workflows and reports.
- Developer: Primary developer for batch and real-time applications using Exstream Dialogue to produce documents for internal and external customers; examples include Confirmation Letters, Enrollment and interactive Plan Profile application.
- Developer: Use Oracle tools to provide complex queries, analyze performance, troubleshoot job failures and manipulate data to support testing
- Project: Fee Disclosure acted as systems analyst and developer on a regulatory compliance
 project. Result was the creation of a fund data warehouse, enhanced OmniPlus confirmation
 letters, updates to statements, development of an event-driven email engine and updates to
 business processes.
- Project: Trust Stable Asset Fund acted as SME informing the design and architecture of Standard's first mutual fund. Involved throughout the project supporting analysis and testing. Fund grew to \$184M within 18 months.
- Project: Invesmart Acquisition/Integration involved throughout this ambitious program to merge the recordkeeping and financial systems of two independent companies within two years.
 Focused on trading, billing, data conversion to OmniPlus and reconciliation sub-projects.
- Support: Provide time-critical technical and business process support to all aspects of Retirement Plans Administration teams and RP financial batch cycles.

- Support: Use in-depth knowledge of OmniPlus recordkeeping system and OmniTrade trading software to diagnose and resolve issues with trades and application interfaces. Implement solutions where possible; document enhancement requirements when necessary.
- Support: Provide tier-1 and tier-2 support to end users of over 100 Retirement Plans applications.

Technical Business Analyst, SunGard, Feb 2002 - Jun 2004

Worked as a consultant to various clients that were upgrading or converting to OmniPlus recordkeeping software

- Provided OmniScript programming solutions for conversion and production requirements, e.g. building custom screens, data extracts and reports.
- Analyzed client business practices and determined ideal OmniPlus solutions. Assisted in all aspects of conversion including programming, data mapping, and client training.

Application Developer - Image Archive Team, Bank One NEO, Jan 2001 - Sep 2001

- Created cross-platform applications for National Enterprise Operations to import images to an NCR Archive and retrieve images via the intranet, using Java, C++ and REXX languages
- Designed and developed load balancing software to increase image conversion throughput by 100%, while eliminating manual system monitoring
- Participated in full development life cycle including design, coding, testing and maintenance

Systems Manager- National Recordkeeping, Bank One IMG, May 1998 - Jan 2001

- Manager of 5 Systems Analysts in the Investment Management Group responsible for maintaining OmniPlus 401(k) recordkeeping database and associated Voice Response and statement applications
- Primary developer for OmniScript language used for creating ad hoc reports and user-defined transactions
- Led conversion effort from OmniPlan to OmniPlus 2.31 and Y2K compliant Plus 5.0, including ongoing release management
- Supported a variety of technical and business functions by developing productivity apps and streamlining procedures. Examples include automating a check distribution process and designing a ticket tracking database for the support group

Education

Kenyon College 1991 - 1995

BA Economics.

Franklin University 1999 - 2001

BS Computer Science, Software Engineering (Java).

freeCodeCamp.com 2016 - 2017

Full Stack Developer Certification (Front end, Back end, Data Visualization)

Key Skills

- Javascript: React.js, redux, D3.js, Node.js, etc
- **SQL**: Oracle, SQL Developer, Toad
- NoSQL: mongoDB, mongoose
- Version Control/Build: Git/GitHub, Webpack, ClearCase, PVCS
- HTML5, CSS: Foundation 6, Bootstrap, etc
- Other languages: Java (Sun Certified 2001), ¡Query, OmniScript, Exstream Dialogue

Profiles

- Portfolio: https://genestd.github.io/portfolio2
- linkedIn*: https://www.linkedin.com/in/davegenest/
- GitHub*: https://github.com/genestd